<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literature Notes on K7288</title>
    <link>https://K7288.github.io/categories/literature-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literature Notes on K7288</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://K7288.github.io/categories/literature-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Froude Numbers</title>
      <link>https://K7288.github.io/posts/froude-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://K7288.github.io/posts/froude-numbers/</guid>
      <description>The Gaits of Bipedal and Quadrupedal Animals Alexander R. The gaits of bipedal and quadrupedal animals. The International Journal of Robotics Research. 1984;
mammals of different sizes tend to move in dynamically similar fashion whenever their Froude numbers $u^2 /gh$ are equal: here u is speed, g is the acceleration of free fall, and h is the height of the hip joint from the ground.
Research Problem description of the gaits of two- and four-legged animals and some of the important optimization criteria(e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of stride length on lower extremity joint kinetics at various gait speeds</title>
      <link>https://K7288.github.io/posts/the-effect-of-stride-length-on-lower-extremity-joint-kinetics-at-various-gait-speeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 10:44:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://K7288.github.io/posts/the-effect-of-stride-length-on-lower-extremity-joint-kinetics-at-various-gait-speeds/</guid>
      <description>The effect of stride length on lower extremity joint kinetics at various gait speeds
 Research question Concepts Notations Background Materials and Methods  Data analysis  1. 数据处理 2. Protocol validation 3. Continuum analysis  main effect analysis SL   4. Torque pulse approximation     Results  Protocol validation Continuum analysis Torque pulse approximation   Conclusion Limits/Further Work Thoughts/Comments  Research question In this study, we investigated how sagittal plane joint moments are affected by a factorial modulation of two important gait parameters: gait speed and stride length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>步速估计综述整理</title>
      <link>https://K7288.github.io/posts/%E6%AD%A5%E9%80%9F%E4%BC%B0%E8%AE%A1%E7%BB%BC%E8%BF%B0%E6%95%B4%E7%90%86/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 22:17:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://K7288.github.io/posts/%E6%AD%A5%E9%80%9F%E4%BC%B0%E8%AE%A1%E7%BB%BC%E8%BF%B0%E6%95%B4%E7%90%86/</guid>
      <description>Toward Pervasive Gait Analysis With Wearable Sensors: A Systematic Review Abstract 对当前的定量步态分析技术进行系统的综述，并提出关键指标，来评估现有的通过可穿戴传感器提取步态特征的方法。它旨在突出这一快速发展的研究领域中的关键进展，并概述研究和临床应用的潜在未来方向。
SECTION III. Methods for Extracting Relevant Gait Features From Wearable Sensors A.文献检索
B. Kinematics
Kinematic information is a well-established set of gait measures in biomechanical analysis.
从惯性传感器获取运动学信息似乎很直观，但是要获得关于人体运动学的准确空间信息仍然很困难：全局失准和integration drift
C.时序特征
D.利用惯性传感器的步速提取
Laudanski et al. [104] reviewed the current research (16 papers in total) on gait speed estimation using inertial sensors, classifying the current gait speed estimation model into three categories: abstraction model (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>基于几何与物理特征融合的智能下肢假肢运动意图识别</title>
      <link>https://K7288.github.io/posts/%E5%9F%BA%E4%BA%8E%E5%87%A0%E4%BD%95%E4%B8%8E%E7%89%A9%E7%90%86%E7%89%B9%E5%BE%81%E8%9E%8D%E5%90%88%E7%9A%84%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BD%E4%B8%8B%E8%82%A2%E5%81%87%E8%82%A2%E8%BF%90%E5%8A%A8%E6%84%8F%E5%9B%BE%E8%AF%86%E5%88%AB/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 20:52:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://K7288.github.io/posts/%E5%9F%BA%E4%BA%8E%E5%87%A0%E4%BD%95%E4%B8%8E%E7%89%A9%E7%90%86%E7%89%B9%E5%BE%81%E8%9E%8D%E5%90%88%E7%9A%84%E6%99%BA%E8%83%BD%E4%B8%8B%E8%82%A2%E5%81%87%E8%82%A2%E8%BF%90%E5%8A%A8%E6%84%8F%E5%9B%BE%E8%AF%86%E5%88%AB/</guid>
      <description>基于几何与物理特征融合的智能下肢假肢运动意图识别Movement intention recognition of intelligent lower limb prosthesis based on the fusion of geometric and physical features
Research question 将关节角表示的几何特征与加速度、角速度表示的物理特征有机融合并应用于智能下肢假肢的运动意图识别
Introduction 传统的意图识别方法所用传感器数量及种类较多, 特征向量维数偏高, 统计特征对短时样本具有不稳定性（在1.3 特征选择与提取有公式证明）。related work没有结合几何和物理。
Methods   采样：健侧大腿、小腿惯性测量单元于摆动相前期所产生的运动时序数据作为样本；
  数据处理：移动平均滤波器滤波去噪
  特征提取：
 几何特征：根据两个传感器的加速度、角速度计算一维的膝关节角，FDA方法提取最值斜率 物理特征：加速度、角速度的均值、方差  均值、方差、最值斜率融合构成25维的特征基构建特征向量
  SVM分类
  Results 13种日常行为进行分类。实验结果：对5类稳态模式: 平地行走、上楼、下楼、上坡和 下坡的识别率达到96.9%, 对8类转换模式的识别率达到97.1%, 对13 种模式的识别率为94.3%。
Highlights 减少了传感器的数量及种类, 降低 了特征向量的维数降低了算法复杂度且避免了滞后性问题, 用加速度、 角速度及膝关节角三个参数共同对人体下肢运动的运动学特点进行表征。
在特征的提取上, 将FDA方法与统计方法相结合, 弥补了仅提取统计特征的不稳定性问题。
Limits/Further Work 对于13种动作的识别率有待提高, 后期工作会集中于对类间相似性相对较强较难区分的动作进行分类, 如: 下楼与下坡, 走到下楼 与走到下坡等. 此外, 关节角度是一个可深度挖掘的几何信息, 如: 除膝关节外的髋关节与踝关节对下肢假肢运动意图中的作用有待进一步探究.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>论文3篇泛读 1-&gt;measurement可靠性(方法比较奇怪或者没有) 2/3-&gt;步态参数拟合</title>
      <link>https://K7288.github.io/posts/measurement%E5%8F%AF%E9%9D%A0%E6%80%A7%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95%E6%AF%94%E8%BE%83%E5%A5%87%E6%80%AA%E6%88%96%E8%80%85%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89-%E6%AD%A5%E6%80%81%E5%8F%82%E6%95%B0%E6%8B%9F%E5%90%88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 11:37:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://K7288.github.io/posts/measurement%E5%8F%AF%E9%9D%A0%E6%80%A7%E6%96%B9%E6%B3%95%E6%AF%94%E8%BE%83%E5%A5%87%E6%80%AA%E6%88%96%E8%80%85%E6%B2%A1%E6%9C%89-%E6%AD%A5%E6%80%81%E5%8F%82%E6%95%B0%E6%8B%9F%E5%90%88/</guid>
      <description>因为不熟悉心相关研究问题，之前做笔记的次数也少，这几篇Literature Notes结构不够清晰，而且过长，下次注意。
三篇文献与选题的关联性差强人意，之后留意/请教一下如何有效查找文献。
1. Reliability of centre of pressure, plantar pressure, and plantar-flexion isometric strength measures: A systematic review COP PP PFisom 三种步态控制measurement 的可靠性
方法：对三个数据库实验进行同行评估 ICC
Background Centre of pressure (COP), plantar pressure (PP), and plantar-flexion isometric strength (PFisom) are often examined in relation to postural control and gait.
Research question Our aim was to systematically review and quality appraise articles addressing the reliability of COP and PP measures in static stance and PFisom measures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
